SANTHIYA SUGUMAR

Software Developer

santhiyasugumar22@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/santhiyasugumar

+917339663947

Full stack and digital developer with totally three + years of experience in developing back-end and front-end features for global companies. My goal is to be an innovative Software Engineer, specializing in the field of front end and back end. I am committed to continuous learning and advancing current software engineering practices.

Work Experience

Logic Research Labs, April 2019 ~ Present

Software Developer



Gathering requirements from client/Business team and estimation. Worked on full Stack web developer, working with the latest frameworks and API

STS, Jan 2017 ~ June 2018

Program Analyst

Responsible for application code and designing. Responsive for database and front end design.



Technology Stack











3 CSS







Education

SASTRA UNIVERSITY 2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science and Engineering (71%)

St. Joseph's Girls Hr. Sec. School 2012

HSC - Higher Secondary Certificate (88%)

St. Joseph's Girls Hr. Sec. School 2010

SSLC - Secondary School Leaving Certificate (93%)

Project Experience

CDAC

https://www.cdac.org.sg/en/



CDAC is a non-profit self-help group for the Chinese community having various supporting scheme. Big architectural application with configurable RBAC

Frontend: Bootstrap 4 , jQuery Backend: Slim framework Database: posgreSQL

API: SendGrid

Role: Designer, Developer

Nubesol

https://nubesol.co.in/



Mobile app transforming the Sugar industry ecosystem.

Frontend and Backend: Zoho Creator, Deluge Script

API: Google Map

Role: Designer, Developer

GradsKey

https://www.gradskey.com



Social Network for Students, Professionals & Academicians Progressive Web App (PWA) with push notification enabled.

Frontend: Bootstrap 4 , jQuery Backend: Codelgniter 3 Database: PosgreSQL

API: SendGrid Role: Developer

Micro Finance ERP System

Microfinance provides end-to-end software solutions for microfinance institutions. It support optimize Multilingual keyboards.

Frontend: Bootstrap 3, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Backend: Slim framework

Database: MySQL API: Bulk SMS API Role: Developer

Achievements

- ✓ Secured First prize in Natural Language Processing, SASTRA University-SRC, Nov 2014.
- ✓ Secured Third prize in Mathematics-4, SASTRA University-SRC Examination, May 2014.

Languages

- ✓ English
- ✓ Tamil Native or Bilingual

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the above details and particulars furnished by me are true to the best of knowledge.